In every woman there is the girl she left behind.
Now and Then is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Lesli Linka Glatter.
Waxing nostalgic about the bittersweet passage from childhood to puberty, four childhood
girlfriends — Teeny, Chrissy, Samantha and Roberta — recall the magical summer of 1970.
During their walk down memory lane, they reconcile
experiences with boys, secrets, bullies and more.
Roberta, played by Christina Ricci.
Roberta, played by Rosie O'Donnell.
Teeny, played by Thora Birch.
Teeny, played by Melanie Griffith.
Samantha, played by Gaby Hoffmann.
Samantha, played by Demi Moore.
Now and Then is a 1995 American coming-of-age comedy-drama film
directed by Lesli Linka Glatter and written by I.
Marlene King.
It stars Christina Ricci, Thora Birch, Gaby Hoffmann, Ashleigh Aston Moore,
Melanie Griffith, Demi Moore, Rosie O'Donnell, and Rita Wilson.
Its plot follows four women who recount a pivotal summer
they shared together as adolescents in 1970.
Now and Then was filmed largely in the Country Walk subdivision off Coffee Bluff Road in Savannah, Georgia (called Shelby, Indiana, in the film, which itself
is based on the real-world town of Winchester, Indiana), using the Gaslight Addition and Old Town Cemetery, highlighting the downtown area.
Additional filming was done in Statesboro, Georgia, in locations including the Bulloch
County Court House and the building now housing the Averitt Center for the Arts.
Although the film received unfavorable reviews upon release, it was a box office
success, grossing $37.5 million against a $12 million budget.
The film is considered a cult classic for its depiction of
girlhood and centering of female friendships.
The film explores themes of 1970s, female friendship,
coming of age, gynecologist, photocopier.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.